<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Wang Wei's Cup of Coffee]]></title>
  <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-30T23:37:59+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://voidstart.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Wang Wei]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 16]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/ror-day-16/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-30T23:28:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/ror-day-16</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Finish first review process</li>
<li>Dig deeper into Active Records</li>
<li>Page 294/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;DRY: Don&rsquo;t Repeat Yourself&rdquo;</h1>

<p>In a sense, the database table/row/column has much resonance with
the OO&rsquo;s class/object/attribute. The dimensions are very similiar.</p>

<p>This is repitition to the humans, to the machines and the different
systems, it&rsquo;s more like saying more or less the same thing in two
langauges. Translation is in order. But since this is defined so
formally in computer languages, can&rsquo;t that be easily translated?</p>

<p>Well, Active Record is all about the automatic translations. There
are rules about names translation, and operations translations.
Naming things is hard, except when you can fixiate on some convention
predefined. Everybody just have to agree on the names.</p>

<p>We are dealing with very intricate stuff in a small kingdom of computer
models and objects and databases and what have you. We can&rsquo;t keep
debating about the names of common things like streets and roads. That
has to be fixed to let us communicate effectively, so we can navigate
without losing the way.</p>

<p>Rails is such fixation. We express one thing, Rails knows the other.
There are exceptions when we want to keep things <em>irregular</em>, Rails allows
that can let us put our exceptions in the system.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 15]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/29/ror-day-15/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-29T22:03:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/29/ror-day-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Review</li>
<li>Fix tests</li>
<li>Setup a production environment</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Production&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Prototype and production are different. The gap may seem complex
but it really shouldn&rsquo;t be. The stuff makes a good prototype should
have good benefits on the production-type also. But then comes the
question of why the gap.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve talked about <a href="http://voidstart.com/blog/2013/11/25/ror-day-11/">Production Qualified</a> before,
about the differences in existence. Now I wonder why one system cannot take the upsides of both.</p>

<p>There really is no reason that a prototype shouldn&rsquo;t be stable and performant. The real problem
is simplicity. Production systems are complex, especially for large scale. It takes extra logic
to optimize/enhance for different situations, such as millions of concurrent users or bad 3G network.
Security risks are high, storage loads are high and data is much more important that can never be
lost. Logging is going to handle both the load and safisticated enough for deep analysis, even
for graphing and data mining purposes.</p>

<p>Why cannot all these be some kind of plugins that could be easily enabled by installation with
a package manager. If the structure is well thought of to enable such reliable extension, there
really should be no reason of why it can&rsquo;t be done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 14]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/28/ror-day-14/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-28T21:58:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/28/ror-day-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Practice the Playtime tasks</li>
<li>286/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Playtime&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Following the book to write the app is straightforward, since everything
is detailed explained.</p>

<p>Playtime is the section without the answers explained, but only the questions given.
I had struggled with some of the questions for quite some time.</p>

<p>So far I have done all the playtime by myself and many of the errors I made are
caused by misunderstanding and carelessness. Through Googling and re-examining
the source codes, eventually the issue will settle.</p>

<p>The hard part about development is sometimes the error message just does not make
sense, you have to apply intuition, play and compare and ask good questions. This
is ultimately about the gap between computer and human, imagine if computer can
figure out all the underlying issues of why something does not work and print
the exact issue right in front of you. Everything is just like cooking recipe, even the error
printed, designed by human. The logic paths are thought first by a human, then coded
into recipes for the execution loop.</p>

<p>Perhaps I should look at machine learning courses for some inspirations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 13]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/27/ror-day-13/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-27T23:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/27/ror-day-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Continue Review</li>
<li>268/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Ajax, Javascript, Css&rdquo;</h1>

<p>This is not something much about Ruby or Rails, just web dev
in general.</p>

<p>Ajax allows interaction without page reload. A request still happens
in the background, but only partical page is obtained. DOM tree largely
remains the same, but part of the tree got replaced.</p>

<p>Javascript is the language used to manipulate the DOM tree, and such
code sources need to be adaptive to content, too. Thus, we could again
use Ruby to generate JS code from templates, just like html pages.
We ends up with: use ruby to do js, use js to do html, use html to do page.
Just an amazing stack.</p>

<p>Css is the language to do styling via several things:</p>

<ul>
<li>Identify some elements in the DOM (via class, id)</li>
<li>Describe the style of that element (font,color,size,margin..)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 12]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/26/ror-day-12/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T20:46:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/26/ror-day-12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Review what I have learn (Retrospective)</li>
<li>268/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Retrospective&rdquo;</h1>

<p>In retrospect, there are several things that are quite fresh to me.</p>

<ul>
<li>MVC thinking</li>
<li>Template transformation ( erb &ndash;> html, js &hellip; )</li>
<li>Ruby block</li>
<li>Pervasive conventions over configuration</li>
<li>Request and State</li>
</ul>


<p>MVC makes the parts of the app easily separated, easy to find what
goes where and reason about.</p>

<p>Transformations from embedded ruby
to other sources are the bridge to generate web pages according to
states, including db and user interactions.</p>

<p>Ruby block shows first order functions, and provides a new way of
thinking about code and behavior. We can pass behaviors around and attach
to another behavior or data.</p>

<p>Conventions make a lot things easier. A lot of hard questions are not
about figuring out how to do, but just choose something, like naming
things and putting things somewhere. Conventions make those no brainers.</p>

<p>Request and state is particular for web development. The server and client
communicates by requests one at a time. To pass on the conversation across
requests, state must be maintained.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 11]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/25/ror-day-11/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-25T20:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/25/ror-day-11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Deployment</li>
<li>264/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Production qualified&rdquo;</h1>

<p>There seems to be always a need to make the testing
environment as simple as possible, for the benefit of quick looping
in experimentation. For real world, however, the priority has changed.
The performance becomes first order, and changes are slow.</p>

<p>The root reason being stability and speed. For any product, it is important to maintain the balance
between delivering a stable, dependenable expectations, and the need
for new functions.</p>

<p>Take it further, it&rsquo;s the difference of existing function and wanted function that matter. If the
need for new/better function outweighs the stability of existing ones, things need to go faster.</p>

<p>In Linux, there&rsquo;s the rule of never break the user&rsquo;s code, respect total backwards compatibility.
Only after years of obsoletion a supported feature could be deleted. Even so, such old products
could still go the history museums.</p>

<p>In today&rsquo;s fast-food world, it becomes rarity to be something that lasts decades. Standing the
test of time is such a beautiful property in modern times.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 10]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/24/ror-day-10/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-24T21:12:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/24/ror-day-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>I18N</li>
<li>244/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Internationalization&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Essentially, every string is a fixed value that is
like enum. However, since texts are so easy to just
type out, people tend to just write them out, rather
than defining any enumeration.</p>

<p>Eventually the solution is to use something like tagging,
which is some function to return a translated version
based on locale.</p>

<p>This is kind of a unique case where a certain special
string literal markings can be useful. In C++ world, there&rsquo;s
a proposal for 2014 which adds physics units to the string
literal, enabling interpretations of physics units at the
compiler level. That could be a great inspiration for i18n.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 9]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/23/ror-day-9/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-23T21:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/23/ror-day-9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Email</li>
<li>Login</li>
<li>Page 207/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Ultimate communication: Email&rdquo;</h1>

<p>I remember somebody said that having emails is the final
stage of advancement of any program. The example being used
was Emacs. Any application complicated enough should at one
time thinking about supporting emails.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s amazing that such an old technology still lives at the
edge of our modern lives. Nothing much about emails have
changed over time. Emails are truly classic, and truly a
basic component of our lives, like beds and wheels. Something
never dies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/ror-day-8/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T19:32:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/ror-day-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progess</h1>

<ul>
<li>CoffeeScript</li>
<li>Page 190/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;CoffeeScript&rdquo;</h1>

<p>It&rsquo;s amazing that people invent one language just to write
another language easier.</p>

<p>The simplest form is Macro languages, those just do short hand
substitutions. Advanced forms would invent its own simpler,
idomatic syntax, to map one structure to another. The advantages
they provide are usually: expressiveness (say more with less),
intuitive (fits people&rsquo;s mind).</p>

<p>Thinking about RoR in general and anything that tries to make
people express more easily, the general idea is the same. You
capture people&rsquo;s intuition, reduce repititions.</p>

<p>I think of RoR as providing a form, just like one of those you fill
at the immigration office. So that you don&rsquo;t have to do your own
composition writing. This is convenient, and enforces a certain level
of quality. The downside is it cuts into your imagination space.</p>

<p>The good thing is you get started and have an idea, then starting to
erase the form and draw your own image. :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/21/ror-day-7/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-21T20:33:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/21/ror-day-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Partial templates</li>
<li>Ajax</li>
<li>Page 163/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Templates as methods&rdquo;</h1>

<p>It&rsquo;s a great idea, actually, more of a general idea.</p>

<p>Templates for web code are like methods that can be
reused, parameterized. This analogy can be extended
to many things, and I believe great things will come
out of it. Think of pictures as methods, videos as
methods. Designs, colors, quotes, that can have <em>API</em>,
can be auto-suggusted or auto-completed, with detailed
parameters. This can be fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/20/ror-day-6/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T14:36:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/20/ror-day-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Custom Db Migration</li>
<li>Custom Notice (Flash)</li>
<li>Handle Invalid request by redirection</li>
<li>Logger</li>
<li>Page 145/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;State of Request&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Between requests, special care should be done to
maintain state. The <em>flash</em> data structure is used,
so far most helpful in error notices.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/19/ror-day-5/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T20:43:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/19/ror-day-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>css,scss</li>
<li>layout (sidebar,banner)</li>
<li>functional tests</li>
<li>page 124/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Functional Tests&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Running tests is like have some robot always
watching your back, which is nice.</p>

<p>The tests written for this demo project follow
such a pattern: add a feature first, then write
a test to ensure <em>some</em> of its behavior.</p>

<p>So far it&rsquo;s hard to imagine the way of writing
tests first, because what to test is yet to be
known.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/18/ror-day-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-18T14:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/18/ror-day-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>More ruby syntax (require,||, bang method, predicate method)</li>
<li>Depot app (pencil and paper design, db migrate/seed, sass, validation)</li>
<li>page 108/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Scaffold&rdquo;</h1>

<p>This is not a new idea. MS word has &ldquo;template&rdquo; documents.
Things are given to solve a particular common problem, with minimal defaults, which
can be viewed as &ldquo;conventions&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Common tasks like add a controller, add a table, a field, where to put stylesheets,
where to put validation, where to put tests&hellip; All have a &ldquo;conventional&rdquo; answer.</p>

<p>Developers&#8217; needs are addressed to be easy to get started. Brilliant.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/ror-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-17T23:43:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/ror-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>Object-Relational Mapping (ORM,Active Record)</li>
<li>Ruby Syntax (array,hash,block,exception,class,module,YAML)</li>
<li>page 70/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;First class function&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Block of codes can be passed to functions as <em>values</em>.
This is a powerful feature of the Ruby language.
The &ldquo;yield&rdquo; call is interesting.  For-loops can be
much different and this solves a lot of abstraction
issue with things like the &ldquo;visitor pattern&rdquo;.</p>

<p><em>Active Records</em> solves another issue with repetative
duplication logic with class objects and database
tables. They are very simular things in a way, but
are much different to access. Active Records is a
device for adapting the differences of access.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/16/ror-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-16T23:07:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/16/ror-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>play with &lt;% %> and &lt;%= %> syntax</li>
<li>review MVC concept</li>
<li>page 52/476</li>
</ul>


<p>(got only about 1 hour of free time today)</p>

<h1>&ldquo;Separation of Concerns&rdquo;</h1>

<p>Model, View, Controller is a good way for humans
to understand computer codes, at least some kinds
of them.</p>

<p>The particular senario this methodology addresses
is a stateful, interactive, perspective application.</p>

<p>There are many kinds of codes. It&rsquo;s hard to model
something like a device driver with MVC.</p>

<p>&ldquo;GUI + storage + business-logic&rdquo; is a very common
case, especially a website.</p>

<p>This convention forces the way of thinking, and makes
it easier to reason. In essense, MVC itself is a
design decision.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RoR Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/15/ror-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-15T22:53:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/15/ror-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Progress</h1>

<ul>
<li>setup rbenv,rails</li>
<li>page 47/476</li>
</ul>


<h1>&ldquo;Convention over Configuration&rdquo;</h1>

<p>I think this philosophy is quite smart.
Naming things is very hard, and a clean
convention solves lot of troubles.
Plus the cost of communication is lower.
Just by looking at a name we can know
some extra information.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[bootstrap...]]></title>
    <link href="http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/14/bootstrap-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T22:35:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://voidstart.github.io/blog/2013/11/14/bootstrap-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, this post marks the beginning of my coder blog.</p>

<p>The making of this blog has been part of my efforts
to become an indie developer. I am kind of idealistic
enough to believe in <a href="http://37signals.com/remote/">remote work</a>.</p>

<p>I am getting interested in web programming recently.
For web development, <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> is of particular
interest. It&rsquo;s neat.  The community is extremely
active and vibrant. I guess I&rsquo;ll start from here,
see how it goes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
